Saurabh Tonpe

Data Scientist

Data Scientist with 3+ years of broad-based experience in building data-intensive applications, overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues. Proficient in predictive modeling, data processing and data mining algorithms as well as programing language like Python. Capable of creating, developing, testing and deploying highly adaptive diverse services to translate business and functional qualifications into substantial deliverables.

7972738838



Pune, India



27 April, 1992

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

StanceCode Technology Pvt. Ltd.

03/2018 - 08/2021

Pune, India

Roles and Responsibility

- Drive the interaction and partnership between the managers to ensure active cooperation in identifying as well as defining analytical needs, and generating the pull-through of insights with the business.
- Demonstrate knowledge and execution of application programming interface development and test automation.
- Utilize analytical and technical expertise to provide insights and proposals to support business improvements.
- Conducted business analysis to understand business needs and requirements to translate into conceptual designs.

Financial Monitoring

Credit card revenue inflow estimator

06/2020 - 08/2021

Tasks:

- Estimate credit card defaulters to get an idea of how much revenue is going to be generated in the coming financial
- Helps in budget management, strategy formulation and reduces error by up to 24%
- Used different classification models like XGboost, SVM, Logistic regression, Decision tree for the best accuracy score.

Robo-Advisory

Customer income classifier

07/2019 - 04/2020

Tasks:

- A classification method has been created to determine whether someone earns more than \$40,000 per year or not.
- This helped in marketing the right banking product to the right customer and thereby increased revenue by 8%.
- Used Pivotel platform to run the app.

Fraud Detection and Prevention

Insurance fraud claim detection

03/2018 - 04/2019

Tasks:

- A model has been created to determine whether a customer is making a fraudulent motor insurance claim.
- By using this model minimizes the loss through a fraudulent claim by 12%.
- Used flask web-app development framework.

GENERAL SKILLS

Machine Learning Data Visualization Pattern Recognition Statistical Analysis Pythonanywhere

Agile Methodologies

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Database/Servers:

My SQL, Mongodb

Programing Language:

 Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Flask, SQL, Machine Learning, Regression, Classification model.

Other Software/Tools:

Windows, Git, AWS, Pivotel, Heroku, Pycharm, Jupytor

Project Responsibilities

Share and update task on Jira, Make mom after the meting, Share daily stat report, Handle client call etc.

EDUCATION

B.E. in Electronics & Telecommunication (2016)

G H Raisoni College of Engineering and Management, Pune

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Play Badminton

Trekking

Watch Tennis